<dashboard showsource="false">
  <label>Documentation</label>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h1>Search Profiling Summary Data</h1>
        <p>This app and its supporting Add-Ons collect summary data about the searches from your environment and stores them in the search_profiling index. There are start and end events for each search, both of which include different sets of fields. Below are descriptions of the fields that are generated for each event type.</p>
       </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h2>Search Granted - Field Descriptions</h2>
        <p>index=search_profiling search_status=granted</p>
        <ul>
					<li><b>_time - </b>The timestamp when the search job was requested.</li>
					<li><b>search_status - </b>Indicates the status of the search. Possible values are ["granted","completed"]. Derived from the "info" field in the search audit log.</li>
					<li><b>user - </b>The username of the user that requested the search.</li>
					<li><b>user_role - </b>Multivalue field representing the roles that this user belongs to on the search head where the search was requested.</li>
					<li><b>app - </b></li>
					<li><b>search_id - </b>Search ID of the search. This value can be used to correlate with scheduler and UI activity logs to get additional details about an individual search.</li>
					<li><b>search_string - </b>The expanded search string that was evaluated by the search head when the search was run.</li>
					<li><b>search_type - </b>Distinguishes between types of searches and whether or not they hit the index. Possible values are ["Raw","Meta","Generating"]. Raw searches pull raw data from an index. Meta searches use commands like "tstats", "mstats" or "metadata" to just look at the indexed metadata from an index. Generating searches don't look an index at all, but instead generate information from some other source, eg. rest, dbinspect. For the purpose of this analysis, we are ignoring generating searches.</li>
					<li><b>search_mode - </b>Describes how the search was generated. Possible values are ["Acceleration","Metadata","Real-time","Scheduled","Typeahead","Subsearch","Dashboard","Ad-hoc"</li>
					<li><b>search_host - </b>The hostname of the search head where the search was requested.</li>
					<li><b>status - </b>Describes quality of search parameters. Possible values are ["BadSearch","StarIdxNoSourcetype","StarStNoIndex","StarSourcetype","StarIdx","NoIndex","NoSourceType","GoodSearch"].</li>
					<li><b>savedsearch_name - </b>The name of the saved search or panel, tf the search was generated by a scheduled search or a dashboard.</li>
					<li><b>api_Start_Time - </b>Epoch timestamp of the start of the search time range.</li>
					<li><b>api_End_Time - </b>Epoch timestamp of the start of the search time range.</li>
					<li><b>*_count - </b></li>
					<li><b>data - </b>List of data sources referenced by the search.</li>
					<li><b>datasource - </b>Extracted field. Multivalue field of data sources referenced by the search. Datasources follow &lt;idx&gt;@&lt;/st&gt; syntax.</li>
					<li><b>idx - </b>Extracted field. Multivalue field of indexes referenced by the search.</li>
					<li><b>data - </b>Extracted field. Multivalue field of sourcetypes referenced by the search.</li>
					<li><b>*_time - </b></li>
					<li><b>usesMacro - </b>Value representing whether the search uses macros that need to be expanded. Possible values are [0,1].</li>
					<li><b>usesBool - </b>Value representing whether the search uses Boolean Operators like "NOT","OR" or "AND". Possible values are [0,1].</li>
					<li><b>dm - </b>Names of any datamodels referenced in the search</li>
        </ul>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h2>Search Completed - Field Descriptions</h2>
        <p>index=search_profiling search_status=completed</p>
        <ul>
					<li><b>_time - </b>The timestamp when the completion of the search job was logged.</li>
					<li><b>search_status - </b>Indicates the status of the search. Possible values are ["granted","completed"]. Derived from the "info" field in the search audit log.</li>
					<li><b>user - </b>The username of the user that requested the search.</li>
					<li><b>user_role - </b>Multivalue field representing the roles that this user belongs to on the search head where the search was requested.</li>
					<li><b>app - </b></li>
					<li><b>search_id - </b>Search ID of the search. This value can be used to correlate with scheduler and UI activity logs to get additional details about an individual search.</li>
					<li><b>search_mode - </b>Describes how the search was generated. Possible values are ["Acceleration","Metadata","Real-time","Scheduled","Typeahead","Subsearch","Dashboard","Ad-hoc"</li>
					<li><b>search_host - </b>The hostname of the search head where the search was requested.</li>
					<li><b>savedsearch_name - </b>The name of the saved search or panel, tf the search was generated by a scheduled search or a dashboard.</li>
					<li><b>api_Start_Time - </b>Epoch timestamp of the start of the search time range.</li>
					<li><b>api_End_Time - </b>Epoch timestamp of the start of the search time range.</li>
					<li><b>scan_count - </b></li>
					<li><b>event_count - </b></li>
					<li><b>result_count - </b></li>
					<li><b>exec_time - </b></li>
					<li><b>total_run_time - </b></li>
        </ul>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h1>Lookup Tables</h1>
        <p>The app relies on a number of lookup tables for keeping track of information about available data sources, data consumption, and use cases. Some are auto-generated and others are manually entered by users. Below are descriptions of the fields that are available in each lookup.</p>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h2>list_index_sourcetypes.csv</h2>
        <p>This lookup keeps track of all of the available indexes and sourcetypes available in Splunk</p>
        <ul>
					<li><b>index - </b>The index the data source lives in.</li>
					<li><b>sourcetype - </b>Indicates the status of the search. Possible values are ["granted","completed"]. Derived from the "info" field in the search audit log.</li>
					<li><b>data - </b>The combination of &lt;index&gt;@&lt;/sourcetype&gt;. The app uses this combination to represent distinct data sources.</li>
        </ul>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h2>data_sources</h2>
        <p>KVStore lookup that lists all of the data sources that your organization has documented.</p>
        <ul>
					<li><b>title - </b>The index the data source lives in.</li>
					<li><b>description - </b>Indicates the status of the search. Possible values are ["granted","completed"]. Derived from the "info" field in the search audit log.</li>
					<li><b>category - </b>The combination of &lt;index&gt;@&lt;/sourcetype&gt;. The app uses this combination to represent distinct data sources.</li>
					<li><b>owner - </b>The index the data source lives in.</li>
					<li><b>datasource - </b>The index the data source lives in.</li>
					<li><b>idx - </b>Indicates the status of the search. Possible values are ["granted","completed"]. Derived from the "info" field in the search audit log.</li>
					<li><b>st - </b>The combination of &lt;index&gt;@&lt;/sourcetype&gt;. The app uses this combination to represent distinct data sources.</li>
					<li><b>value - </b>Indicates the status of the search. Possible values are ["granted","completed"]. Derived from the "info" field in the search audit log.</li>
					<li><b>use_cases - </b>The combination of &lt;index&gt;@&lt;/sourcetype&gt;. The app uses this combination to represent distinct data sources.</li>
        </ul>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
  <row>
    <panel>
      <html>
        <h2>use_cases</h2>
        <p>KVStore lookup that lists all of the use cases that your organization has documented.</p>
        <ul>
					<li><b>title - </b>The index the data source lives in.</li>
					<li><b>description - </b>Indicates the status of the search. Possible values are ["granted","completed"]. Derived from the "info" field in the search audit log.</li>
					<li><b>category - </b>The combination of &lt;index&gt;@&lt;/sourcetype&gt;. The app uses this combination to represent distinct data sources.</li>
					<li><b>owner - </b>The index the data source lives in.</li>
					<li><b>value - </b>Indicates the status of the search. Possible values are ["granted","completed"]. Derived from the "info" field in the search audit log.</li>
					<li><b>value_description - </b>The combination of &lt;index&gt;@&lt;/sourcetype&gt;. The app uses this combination to represent distinct data sources.</li>
        </ul>
      </html>
    </panel>
  </row>
</dashboard>